Guide to the Douglas E. Hammond Collection of Computer Manuals
Douglas E. Hammond Collection of Computer Manuals
1962-1983
1962 1983
Hammond Douglas E.
MC 00480
The Douglas E. Hammond Collection of Computer Manuals contains manuals for computer software and hardware primarily created by IBM. There is a small segment of manuals for software and hardware created by the Applied Data Research group. The manuals range in date from 1962 to 1983. Some major types of items covered include virtual machines, operating systems, customer information control systems and information systems. They are primarily targeted to the IBM mainframe platform.
Douglas E. Hammond was a former employee of IBM who worked with IBM mainframes and collected these manuals from the early computer era. They date as far back as 1962 and go through 1983. These manuals showcase the type of products that IBM was creating during the exponential rise of computer usage and the development of the Internet. As is well known, the computer as well as IBM as a company have evolved and changed greatly over time. The items in this collection are evidence of both the change over a two decade period. They also add to a more complete history of computing and simulation. Hammond also collected some manuals from the Applied Data Research group that have threads of connection to some of the IBM manuals, such as the subject of COBOL, the Common Business-Oriented Language, a very early programming language.
28 linear feet
56 archival boxes
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
Gift of Don Hammond 2013 March (accession no. 2013.0057)
This collection is arranged into 17 series: 1. IBM 8100 Information System 2. IBM Application Program 3. IBM Field Developed Program 4. IBM Installation Management 5. IBM Installed User Program 6. IBM Internally Developed Program 7. IBM Licensed Program 8. Other Types of IBM Manuals 9. IBM Program Logic 10. IBM Program Product 11. IBM Student Text 12. IBM Systems 13. IBM System Library Supplement 14. IBM System Reference Library 15. IBM Technical Bulletin 16. IBM World Trade Systems Center 17. Applied Data Research. The files in each series are arranged alphabetically by title. The majority of the collection is contained within the IBM Program Product and the IBM Systems series.
Douglas E. Hammond was a former employee of IBM who worked with IBM mainframes and collected these manuals from the early computer era. They date as far back as 1962 and go through 1983. These manuals showcase the type of products that IBM was creating during the exponential rise of computer usage and the development of the Internet. As is well known, the computer as well as IBM as a company have evolved and changed greatly over time. The items in this collection are evidence of both the change over a two decade period. They also add to a more complete history of computing and simulation. Hammond also collected some manuals from the Applied Data Research group that have threads of connection to some of the IBM manuals, such as the subject of COBOL, the Common Business-Oriented Language, a very early programming language.
The Douglas E. Hammond Collection of Computer Manuals contains manuals for computer software and hardware primarily created by IBM. There is a small segment of manuals for software and hardware created by the Applied Data Research group. The manuals range in date from 1962 to 1983. Some major types of items covered include virtual machines, operating systems, customer information control systems and information systems. They are primarily targeted to the IBM mainframe platform.
Hammond Douglas E.; Hammond Don; International Business Machines Corporation; Applied Data Research, Inc.; History Computers; History of Computing and Simulation; Programming languages (Electronic computers)
- IBM 8100 Information System Manuals, 1979; 1979 1979; 0.06 linear feet; 6 archival folders
  This series is arranged first alphabetically and, in the case of the same title, then chronologically.
  The IBM 8100 Information System Manuals series contains manuals about the IBM 8100 Information System.
  - 8100 Information System Network Management Planning Guide, Jun 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Distributed Processing Control Execuitve. Printer Operations, Aug 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Distributed Processing Control Executive. Programming: Guide to Host Communication for Application Programmers, Jul 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Distributed Processing Control Executive. Remote Job Entry: Installation and Operation, Dec 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - DPCX Host Support: Introduction to Application Programming, Jun 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Host Command Facility. General Information, Aug 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- IBM Application Program, 1969; 0.05 linear feet; 5 archival folders
  The IBM Application Program series contains computer manuals underneath that heading.
  - Problem Language ANalyzer (PLAN). (1130-CX-25X, 360A-CX-26X, 360A-CX-27X) Application Description Manual, Jan 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Problem Language ANalyzer (PLAN). Program Description Manual, Nov 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Problem Language ANalyzer (PLAN). Users' Introduction, Jun 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - System/360 Flowchart (360A-SE-22X). Operator's Manual, Oct 1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - System/360 Flowchart. User's Manual, Oct 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- IBM Field Developed Program, 1976-1980; 0.26 linear feet; 26 archival folders
  The IBM Field Developed Program series contains computer manuals underneath that heading.
  - Data Retrieval/Manipulation Utility, Jan 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - IBM 8100/DPCX IBM 3790. Data Set Utility Program, Feb 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - IBM 8100/DPCX IBM 3790. Sort/Merge Program, Sep 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - IBM Field Developed Program, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Online Preparation of Video/370 Format, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Program Description/Operations Manual. IBM 8100/DPCX 3790 Disk Utility, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Program Description/Operations Manual. IBM 8100/DPCX 3790 Sort/Merge Program, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Program Description/Operations Manual. VS APL Financial Planning System, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - System/370. Batch Terminal Simulator-Teleprocessing Network Simulator, Sep 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - System/370. DASD Seek Simulator, Feb 1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - System/370. Generalized Performance Analysis Reporting. Extended Support, Aug 1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - System/370. GIS/VS 3270 Formatting Aid, Jul 1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - System/370. GTFPARS. Extended Support, Dec 1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - System/370. IMSASAP II. Extended Support, Jun 1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - System/370. IMS/VS Performance Analysis Reporting (IMS PARS). Extended Support, May 1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - System/370. IMS/VS Virtual Storage Analysis, Feb 1977 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - System/370. PF Key Simulator for SPF-2, Jan 1978 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - System/370. System Library Subscription Service (SLSS) Control, Jan 1978 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - System/370. TSO/VTAM Data Set Print, Jan 1980 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - System/370. VIDEO/370 Offline Data Entry, Jan 1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - System/370. VIDEO/370 On-line Status Display, Jan 1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - System/370. Virtual Machine Facility/370 Performance/Monitor Analysis. Extended Support, Apr 1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - System/370. VTAM Interface to VIDEO/370, Apr 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - System/370. VTAM PARS. Extended Support, Jan 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Systems Guide, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Technical Newsletter, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- IBM Installation Management, 1974-1978; 1974 1978; 0.07 linear feet; 7 archival folders
  The IBM Installation Management series contains computer manuals underneath that heading.
  - Change Management/Tracking (CM/T), DP Accounting for IMS/VS (DPA), Service Level Reporter (SCR) General Information Manual, Jul 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Component Failure Impact Analysis, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Energy Conservation and Management in Data Processing Installations, Sep 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Installation Management Bibliography, Jun 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - An Introduction to Structured Programming in PL/I, Jun 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Management Controls for Data Processing, Apr 1976 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Problem and Change Management in Data Processing. A Survey and Guide, Aug 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- IBM Installed User Program, 1973-1978; 0.12 linear feet; 12 archival folders
  The IBM Installed User Program series contains computer manuals underneath that heading.
  - A Departmental Reporting System Users Guide, Feb 1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - IBM Installed User Program, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - IMS Application Development Facility Version 1 Release 2. Program Description/Operations Manual, Nov 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - IMS Version 2.3 Productivity Aids, Feb 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Query-by-Example. Program Description/Operations Manual, Sep 1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Query-by-Example. Terminal User's Guide, Sep 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - SCRIPT/370 Version 3 User's Guide, Sep 1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - System/370. OS/VS and DOS/VS. OS and DOS CICS/VS COBOL Call Interface, Dec 1975 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - System/370. OS/VS1 Priority Queue Aging, Jun 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - System/370. Testing and Debugging Online with CICS/VS, Feb 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Test IMS/VS Utilities, Jul 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - VS1 Performance Tool (VS1 PT). Program Description and Operation Manual, Nov 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- IBM Internally Developed Program, 1976-1981; 1976 1981; 0.11 linear feet; 11 archival folders
  The IBM Internally Developed Program series contains computer manuals underneath that heading.
  - System/370. APL Data Interface, Jul 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - System/370. IMS-CMS Data Link for VM/370, Jan 1979 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - System/370. Query-by-Example, Sep 1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - System/370, 4300, 303X. 3101 Pass Through VM/370 Support, Sep 1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - System/370, APLSV, APL/CMS and VS APL. Departmental Reporting System, Jan 1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - System/370, IMS/360, IMS/VS. IMS Space Management Utilities-II, May 1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - System/370, IMS/VS. IMS Application Development Facility, Dec 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - System/370, OS/VS. Audit File Compare, May 1980 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - System/370, OS/VS. Optimize Telpak Communication Costs, Nov 1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - System/370, OS/VS1. OS/VS1 Networking Node to MVS, SVS and VS1, Jan 1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - System/370, VS APL, APLSV. General Cross Assembler Generator, Jan 1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- IBM Licensed Program, 1978-1980; 1978 1980; 0.04 linear feet; 4 archival folders
  The IBM Licensed Program series contains computer manuals underneath that heading.
  - Distributed Processing Programming Executive. Program Summary, Sep 1980 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - IBM 8100 Information System Host Command Facility, Mar 1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - IBM Virtual Machine Facility/370 System Extensions Program Product. Specifications, Mar 1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - VSE/Advanced Functions System Information, Feb 1979 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Other Types of IBM Manuals, 1962-1983; 1962 1983; 1.375 linear feet; 2 and 3/4 archival boxes
  The Other Types of IBM Manuals series contains IBM computer manuals of which only one or two of the types exist in the collection as well as some IBM brochures.
  - 8101 Storage and Input/Output Unit Relocate/Setup Instructions, Mar 1980-Apr 1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 8775 Display Terminal Models 1, 2, 11 and 12 Setup Instructions and Configuration Information, May 1980-Sep 1980 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Account Management Planning Guide. Central Data Processing Facility, Aug 1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Brochures for Products, 1975-1981 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Business Systems Planning. Information Systems Planning Guide, Oct 1978 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Communication Systems Management Basic Concepts, Aug 1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Data Processing Division Customer Bulletins and Support Bulletins, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Data Processing Glossary, Oct 1977 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Demonstration Guide Marketing Documentation. APL Demonstrations. APL Language, Financial Planning System, Econometric Planning Language, Feb 1977 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Demonstration Guide Marketing Documentation. A Departmental Reporting System, Sep 1976 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Developed Program. System/370, IMS/VS. DBPrototype II Release 2, Oct 1978 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Disk Storage Technology, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Diskette General Information Manual, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Division of Consolidated Foods. System/370, CICS/VS. Cash Application System, Jan 1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Field Engineering Programming System General Information, May 1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Information Systems Group National Accounts Division Customer Bulletin, Jun 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Manual for the VM/370 Measurement Facility, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Marketing Publications KWIC Index, Dec 1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Planning Guide. VM/System Product System IPO/Extended, Feb 1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Reference Manual for IBM 1401 Data Processing System, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Series/1 Digest, Jun 1979 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Series/1 Model 5 4955 Processor and Processor Features Description, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - SQL/Data System for VSE: A Relational Data System for Application Development, Apr 1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - System/370 Auditability and Productivity Information Catalog, Sep 1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - System/370 Catalog of Language and Sort Program Products, Nov 1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Systems Auditability and Control. Audit Practices, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Systems Auditability and Control. Control Practices, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - System Control Programming for OS/VS2 Release 2, Job Entry Subsystem 2 (JES2) and VM/370 - Support Systems for large System/370s, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Systems Library Subscription Service (SLSS) Bulletin, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Systems Product. VSE System Installation Productivity Option/Extended: Release 3.0 User's Guide, Nov 1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Systems and Products Guide, Jan 1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Systems and Products Guide. Expanded Small and Office Systems Information, Dec 1982 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Tape Specifications for IBM One-Half Inch Tape Drives at: 556 and 800 BPI and 3200 FCI, May 1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- IBM Program Logic, 1966-1975; 1.5 linear feet; 3 archival boxes
  The IBM Program Logic series contains computer manuals underneath that heading.
  - IBM System/360 Conversion Aids: FORTRAN IV-to-PL/I Language Conversion Program for IBM System/360 Operating System, Jan 1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - IBM System/360 Disk and Tape Operating Systems Assembler (D), Jun 1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Assembler (32K), 1966 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Basic Direct Access Method, Jul 1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Catalog Management, Dec 1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Direct Access Device Space Management, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Fixed-Task Supervisor, Nov 1968 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. FORTRAN IV (H) Compiler, Jun 1970 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Indexed Sequential Access Methods, Jul 1969 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Initial Program Loader and Nucleus Initialiation Program, July 1969 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Input/Output Support (OPEN/CLOSE/EOV), Nov 1968 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Introduction to Control Program Logic, Nov 1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Job Management, Jul 1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Job Management with MFT, Mar 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. MFT Supervisor (1 of 2), Mar 1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. MFT Supervisor (2 of 2), Mar 1972 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. MVT Job Management, Apr 1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. MVT Job Management, Nov 1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. MVT Supervisor (1 of 2), May 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. MVT Supervisor (2 of 2), May 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Sequential Access Methods, Jul 1969 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Time Sharing Option (TSO) Control Program (1 of 2), Mar 1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - IBM System/360 Operating System. Time Sharing Option (TSO) Control Program (2 of 2), Mar 1972 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - OS Assembler (F) Logic, Mar 1973 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - OS I/O Supervisor Logic, Feb 1972 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - OS OPEN/CLOSE/EOV Logic, Mar 1972 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- IBM Program Product, 1971-1981; 1971 1981; 10.03 linear feet; 20 archival boxes and 3 archival folders
  The IBM Program Product series contains computer manuals underneath that heading.
  - ACF/NCP/VS. Network Control Program. System Support Programs. Installation, May 1979 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - ACF/NCP/VS. Network Control Program. System Support Programs. Messages, May 1979 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - ACF/NCP/VS. Network Control Program. System Support Programs. Utilities, May 1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Advanced Communications Function for TCAM and NCP (ACF/TCAM - NCP). Bibliography and Master Index, Apr 1978 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Advanced Communications Function for VTAM. Programming, Oct 1980 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Advanced Communications Function for VTAM (ACF/VTAM). Concepts and Planning. ACF/VTAM Release 1, Aug 1977 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Advanced Communications Function for VTAM (ACF/VTAM). Debugging Guide, Nov 1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Advanced Communications Function for VTAM (ACF/VTAM). General Information, Jan 1978 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Advanced Communications Function for VTAM (ACF/VTAM). Installation Guide, ACF/VTAM Release 1, Nov 1977 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Advanced Communications Function for VTAM (ACF/VTAM). Messages and Codes, ACF/VTAM Release 1, Nov 1977 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Advanced Communications Function for VTAM (ACF/VTAM). Network Operating Procedures, ACF/VTAM Release 1, Nov 1977 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Advanced Communications Function for VTAM (ACF/VTAM). Operation, ACF/VTAM Release 2, Mar 1979 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Advanced Communications Function for VTAM (ACF/VTAM). System Programmer's Guide, ACF/VTAM Release 2, May 1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Advanced Communications Function for VTAM (ACF/VTAM). Macro Language Reference, ACF/VTAM Release 1, Dec 1978 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Basic Telecommunications Access Method Extended Support. Logic, Jan 1979 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Code and Go FORTRAN for OS and VM/370 (CMS). Specifications, Nov 1972 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). General Information Manual, Mar 1975 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Messages and Codes Manual, May 1975 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Subset User's Guide (DOS), May 1975 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1.2. General Information Manual, Nov 1975 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 3. Application Programmer's Reference Manual (Command Level), Feb 1977 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 3. Application Programmer's Reference Manual (Command Level), Apr 1977 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 3. Application Programmer's Guide (Macro Level), Feb 1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 3. General Information, Feb 1977 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. Application Programmer's Reference Manual (Macro Level), Jun 1978 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. General Information, Apr 1978 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. IBM 3600/3630 Guide, Jun 1978 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. IBM 3650 Guide, Jun 1978 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. IBM 3767 and 3770 Guide, Jun 1978 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. IBM 3790 Guide, Jun 1978 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. Introduction to Program Logic, Jun 1978 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. Messages and Codes, Jun 1978 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. Messages and Codes, Aug 1978 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. Operator's Guide, Aug 1978 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. Problem Determination Guide, Jun 1978 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. Problem Determination Guide, Aug 1978 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. Program Logic (DOS/VS) (1 of 3), Jun 1978 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. Program Logic (DOS/VS) (2 of 3), Jun 1978 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. Program Logic (DOS/VS) (3 of 3), Jun 1978 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. System/Application Design Guide, Jun 1978 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. System/Application Design Guide, Aug 1978 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. System Programmer's Reference Manual (1 of 2), Aug 1978 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. System Programmer's Reference Manual (2 of 2), Aug 1978 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4. System Programmer's Guide (OS/VS), Aug 1978 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 4.1. Master Index, Jul 1979 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Customer Information Control System/Virtual Storage (CICS/VS). Version 1, Release 5. General Information, Sep 1979 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - DB/DC Data Dictionary. Application Guide, Jul 1979 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - DB/DC Data Dictionary. General Information Manual, Oct 1978 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - DB/DC Data Dictionary. General Information Manual, Dec 1978 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - DB/DC Data Dictionary. Installation Guide, Jul 1979 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - DB/DC Data Dictionary. Terminal User's Guide and Command Reference, Jul 1979 (Box 14, Folder 5)